# AbdulBateen Jolaosho

Ogun State, Nigeria

bataino.ronaldo@gmail.com

+2349066299190

linkedin.com/in/bataino-ronaldo

# **Summary**

AbdulBateen is a vast software engineer with 3 years of experience. He is experienced in building IT solutions for different industries. business owners, pharmacies and startups He is an entrepreneur, which makes him an excellent fit for startups and upcoming firms.

He has participated in the launching of different products such as SoftgreenGo and Rentout. Abdulbateen is not afraid of failing but rather sees failure as a stepping stone to success.

# **Experience**

#### Technical Lead/Co-Founder

Softgreen Agribusiness Limited

Aug 2022 - Present (4 months +)

#### Lead Frontend Engineer

Rentout

Apr 2022 - Present (8 months +)

Managed the Frontend Architecture and design.

Designed and developed main website features.

Lead and unified the frontend and backend architecture

#### Seasonal Fullstack Developer

Shado Books Pvt Ltd

May 2022 - Jul 2022 (3 months)

Upgraded design of a legacy e-commerce website.

Implemented Firebase push notification on Blood Donation Mobile Application.

Worked majorly with PHP, Bootstrap and Android Studio.

# Full Stack Developer

Voxforem Technologies

Mar 2022 - Jun 2022 (4 months)

Developed IOS and Android applications for smart school within 2 months using Ionic Vue.

Developed custom modules for Dolibarr, an open-source CRM.

Worked by Waterfall Methodologies.

#### Full-stack Developer

TechLava Softwares

Sep 2020 - Jun 2022 (1 year 10 months)

Built 3 websites and admin panels with a team of 3 all within 6 months.

Supervised a team of contracted web developers.

Worked with technologies such as Sphp, Bootstrap, JavaFx and Vue.

#### **Mobile Developer**

**Techiehealth Pharmacy** 

May 2021 - May 2022 (1 year 1 month)

Designed and implemented mobile UI designs to ionic vue Components.

collaborated with other developers to configure an inventory management system in Python.

Worked by Agile methodologies, with a sprint of 2 weeks.

Completed the company's website in 2 weeks together with other developers.

#### **■ ■** Freelance Web Developer

Shado Books Pvt Ltd

Oct 2021 - Oct 2021 (1 month)

Worked mainly with technologies such as Laravel and Bootstrap.

Upgraded and redesigned frontends for school management software.

Came up with proposal on ways to improve website's architecture.

#### **Frontend Developer**

MJM GROUP

Aug 2018 - Sep 2020 (2 years 2 months)

Developed and designed website using Bootstrap and Javascript.

Worked on simple tasks with Java and JavaFx.

#### **Education**

### Federal university of Agriculture, Abeokuta

Under Graduate, Mechatronics, Robotics, and Automation Engineering 2019 - Present

#### Skills

Team Management • Ionic • Android • Vue • Laravel • JavaScript • PHP • Bootstrap • Java • JavaFX